A Guide to the Thomas Sigismond Stribling Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6485
Thomas Sigismond Stribling Collection 1937-1939
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6485
22 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit 1961 Mar 15
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Description of Thomas Sigismond Stribling by Frank Stone, 1937 Nov 12; TMs, 1 p.
    [Describes how Stribling came to the Chemical Bank & Trust Company, New York, to pick up a copy of a check list of his publications compiled by Stone; says that Stribling promised Stone one of his manuscripts as payment for Stone's labor of love in compiling Stribling's work; says that Stribling talked about his new novel
    The Parade of The Wooden Soldiers
    he had just delivered to Doubleday Doran for publication and he got information on investment trust stocks.]
  - Story, " The Dip ", [1939]; TMs, 28 p. (carbon)
    [Addressed to Curtis Brown. ]
- Letters
  - Frank Stone to Thomas Sigismond Stribling, 1937 Jan 16; TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Discusses his collection of Stribling first editions; encloses a clipping from the
    Herald Tribune
    with rare praise of Stribling as a result of the uproar connected with Maybeth Mitchell's book; offers to do a bibliography of Stribling's first editions.]
  - Thomas Sigismond Stribling to [Fred] Frank Stone, 1937 Feb 2; TLS, 1 p. w/env
    [Gives him permission to do a bibliography of his "firsts"; talks of an upcoming trip to New Orleans. ]
  - Thomas Sigismond Stribling to Frank Stone, 1937 May 24; TLS, 1 p. w/env
    [Answers questions in regard to his early publications; suggests second hand book store in New York for rare copies, especially one of
    Red Sand
    names the magazines in which he published children's stories; offers to have a look at Stone's check list; announces plans to come to New York in the summer.]
  - Frank Stone to Thomas Sigismond Stribling, 1937 Jun 2; TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Encloses a 2 page, typed list of Stribling's works; discusses his progress with the bibliography; says he has not found a copy of
    yet; hopes to get more information from the Library of Congress; asks for more information regarding Stribling's other work.]
  - Frank Stone to Messrs. Reilly and Lee, 1937 Jun 8; TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Tries to get publishing company's help in regard to Stribling's
    The Cruise of The Drydock
    , to be published by their predecessor, Reilly & Britton, 1917; presents specific questions.]
  - M. C. Peterson, Reilly & Lee Co., to Frank Stone, 1937 Jun 8; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says he is unable to locate the records of Reilly & Britton regarding the publication of the book and that on longtime employee says only one edition was issued; tells him that the plates were destroyed some years ago.]
  - Frank Stone to Thomas Sigismond Stribling, 1937 Jun 8; TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Expresses gratitude for the return of the checklist, the catalogue and a list of short stories that Stribling prepared; says the checklist will appear in
    Publisher's Weekly
    promises to have more questions for him at their meeting in the summer.]
  - H. E. Maule to Frank Stone, 1937 Jun 9; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says that the company's records show that there was an edition of 350 copies of
    Unfinished Cathedral
    prior to publication in 1934; says there were 250 signed copies, 1935, prior to publication and that no copies of the advance edition are left; suggests advertising in
    Publishers Weekly
    . ] (includes autograph note)
  - Frank Stone to M. C. Peterson, 1937 Jun 10; TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Thanks him for the information in regard to The Cruise of the Drydock. ]
  - Frank Stone to H. E. Maule, 1937 Jun 10; TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Thanks him for information given in regard to Stribling's two books and for the advice given to advertise in
    . ]
  - Frank Stone to Jacob [Nathaniel] Blanck, 1937 Jun 14; TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Sends the checklist; says he has not been able to find a copy of
    apologizes for sending him a carbon copy; wants to hang on to the original as Thomas Sigismond Stribling made notations on it.]
  - Frank Stone to Thomas Sigismond Stribling, 1937 Jul 8; TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Promises him copies of
    when the checklist appears in it; says he located a brand new copy of
    Cruise of The Drydock
    at a bookshop in New York City; requests some information on he publishing of the book to put it the bibliography.]
  - Frank Stone to Thomas Sigismond Stribling, 1937 Aug 28; TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Sends him a copy of
    which contains a checklist of his works; looks forward to the compilation of the bibliography; says he will ask for information on the location of manuscripts.]
  - C. M. Meredith to Frank Stone, 1937 Sep 24; ALS, 1 p. w/env
    [Informs Stone that he has two different copies of Thomas Sigismond Stribling's book
    Fombombo
    and gives a detailed description of the books; forwards this information because Stone's checklist does not mention a "first" and a "later" issue.]
  - Frank Stone to C. M. Meredith, 1937 Sep 29; TL, 1 p. (carbon)
    [Says he would like to purchase the copy of
    bound in grey cloth with green lettering; promises to make further checks on the publication of the book.]
  - Thomas Sigismond Stribling to Frank Stone, 1938 Apr 12; TLS, 1 p. w/env
    [Expresses pleasure that Stone likes
    Three Bars of Flesh
    mentions a complimentary review of it in the
    New York Times
    writes from Florida where he is doing short stories; plans to go to Germany this summer for a lengthy stay.]
  - Thomas Sigismond Stribling to Frank Stone, 1939 Feb 23; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says he will send a manuscript with Easter greetings for Stone's collection; says the story will appear in the
    Saturday Evening Post
  - Edith Haggard to Frank Stone, 1939 Feb 28; TLS, 1 p.
    [Sends him Thomas Sigismond Stribling's manuscript, "
    The Dip
    " and a letter, according to Stribling's instructions.]
- Miscellaneous
  - Correction sheet for East is East by Thomas Sigismond Stribling, Corrections
  - Thomas Sigismond Stribling to "Dear Stone", TL, 1 p.
    [Includes list of books which contain stories by Stribling.]